欢迎大家，这是凝聚态课程的第十九讲
welcome back everyone it's a nineteenth
lecture of the condensed matter course
快到第六周结束了，我知道很难继续下去了，是你
nearing the end of sixth week I know
it's hard to keep keep going on it's you
知道六周结束时每个人都很累，但是我们真的越来越
know the end of six week everyone gets
pretty tired but we're really getting
现在已经接近本课程的结尾了，所以您可以通过打开电源知道
pretty close to the end of this course
now so it's you know power on through so
当我们上次离开讨论磁学时，我们决定
when we left off last time we were
talking about magnetism we decided a
一次开始思考磁性的好地方是一次原子
good place to start thinking about
magnetism was one atom at a time so
真正考虑原子磁性
really thinking about atomic magnetism
磁性，我们已经写下哈密顿量，实际上是
magnetism and we had written down the
Hamiltonian actually the Hamiltonian for
一个磁场中的一个原子中有一个电子，我们决定将其写入
one electron in one atom in a magnetic
field and we decided we would write it
作为零磁场下电子的哈密顿量
as the Hamiltonian for that electron in
zero magnetic field that's just the
吸引原子核的动能加上两个项，第一个项是
kinetic energy in the attraction to the
nucleus plus two terms the first term is
玻尔磁子磁场点成轨道角动量加G自旋
Bohr Magneton magnetic field dotted into
orbital angular momentum plus G spin
角动量和第二项平方超过2m平方，其中a是
angular momentum and the second term a
squared over 2m a squared where a is the
向量势，其del cross a等于B现在，这两个术语都具有名称
vector potential its del cross a equals
B okay now these two terms have names
这里的第一个术语称为顺磁术语，这里的这个术语
this first term over here is known as
the paramagnetic term and this term here
被称为反磁性术语，您可能会猜到这是
is known as the diamagnetic term and as
you might guess it's this term that's
这个术语通常负责修复磁性
typically responsible repairing
magnetism in this term which is
通常负责反磁性，这个术语实际上是相当
typically responsible for diamagnetism
and this term it's actually fairly
很明显为什么这个词要负责权力
obvious why it is that this term is
going to be responsible for power
磁场通常只是磁场与磁场的耦合
magnetism generally this is just
coupling of the magnetic field to the
旋转或覆盖电子的动量，现在可以了
spin or overlying the mentum of the
electron and the okay now it's a little
由于减号而复杂，但自旋要订购
complicated because of the minus signs
but the spin wants to order the
上覆动量都想指向B相对，使得B的负能量
overlying momentum both want to point
opposite B such that the neg energy of
这将变为负数，如果自旋Orval动量与B相反，
this becomes negative and if the spin
Orval a momentum is opposite B that
表示磁矩与B方向相同，因为
means the magnetic moment is the same
direction as B because the charge of
电子为负，所以力矩指向与角动量相反的方向
electron is negative so the moment
points opposite of the angular momentum
所以无论如何还是为了降低能量
so anyway to or in order to lower the
energy the
B相对的B线和/或Belanger精神相对的B线旋转，因此
spins line up opposite B and/or Belanger
mentum lines up opposite B and therefore
当所有在同一方向上排列的那一刻是B并且你有
the moment all lines up in the same
direction is B and you have
现在您可能会注意到这两个术语的顺磁性是
paramagnetism now one thing you may
notice about these two terms is this
功率磁铁的磁项在B中是线性的，而该项在b中是二次的
power magnet magnetic term is linear in
B whereas this term is quadratic in b
和b，因此一般来说，小的是线性的，反过来是功率的磁
and b and so generally for small be the
linear in turn be the power magnetic
只要没有特别好的理由，这个术语将占主导地位
term is going to dominate as long as
there is not a particularly good reason
为什么功率磁项将被抑制或以某种方式甚至为零，那么
why the power magnetic term is going to
be suppressed or somehow even zero then
反磁术语是无关紧要的，我们只需要担心功率
the diamagnetic term is irrelevant and
we just have to worry about the power
具有磁性的术语，我们会发现该术语为0或被抑制的情况
magnetic term we will find occasions
where this term is 0 or is suppressed
然后反磁项将有机会主导物理学，但我们
and then a diamagnetic term will have a
chance to dominate the physics but we're
首先要专注于这一点，它将变得更加重要
going to focus on this one first
figuring it's going to be more important
所以让我们用这个学期，我们要做的就是
so let's a take this term and what we're
going to want to do is we're going to
现在想稍微简化一下，我们可以做的一件事就是可以将它们加在一起
want to simplify it a little bit now one
thing we can do is we can add together
轨道角动量的角动量求和
the angular momentum of the orbital
angular momentum to get the total
角动量J是L加Sigma，但您会注意到，这不是我们
angular momentum J is L plus Sigma but
you'll notice that's not what we
实际上在哈密顿方程式中，我们有L加G Sigma现在您可能已经了解到
actually have in the Hamiltonian we have
L plus G Sigma now you may have learned
在您或您应该已经在原子物理学课程中学习到
in your or you should have learned in
your atomic physics course that under
您知道J的大小L的大小
conditions where you know the magnitude
of J the magnitude of L the magnitude of
Sigma您可以用一些有效的G因子G重写整个术语
Sigma you can rewrite that entire term
in terms of some effective G factor G
有效的称为Al和AG因子，通常用上标j
effective known as Al and AG factor
usually written with a superscript j mu
B BJ并且有一些公式可以让您获得G为有效G
B BJ and there's some formula that
allows you to get the G the effective G
从G和J的量级到L的量级的因子
factor from G and the magnitude of J and
the magnitude of L in the magnitude
西格玛（Sigma），如果您知道这些，则该公式不是本课程的一部分，但我相信
Sigma if you know these that formula is
not part of this course but I believe
这是您另一门课程的一部分，所以如果您要参加，您可能应该知道
it's part of your other course so you
probably should know it if you're taking
您将不会被要求在原子物理学课程中推导它
the atomic physics course you won't be
asked to derive it in this course you
在其他过程中，可能会被要求以任何比率得出道德是您
may be asked to derive in the other
course any rate the moral is that you
可以总结一下，您可以将轨道和自旋角动量加在一起
can just sum you can put together the
orbital and spin angular momenta and
在您知道JL和Sigma是什么的情况下，您只需想到
under the conditions that you know what
JL and Sigma are you can just think of
这是一个在磁场中重新定向的单个角动量矢量，
this as a single angular momentum vector
that reorients in a magnetic field and
我们的条款可以重置可以总结
the
our term can be reset can be summarized
正因为如此，这是哈密顿主义下的一个相当简单的术语
as as this so it's a fairly simple term
in the Hamiltonian under those
我们可以将其视为单个总角动量的条件
conditions where we can just think of it
as a single total angular momentum being
通过磁场重新定向，但实际上这个故事要多一些
reoriented by the magnetic field but in
fact the story is a little more
比这复杂，比这更复杂，因为我们有
complicated than this and it's more
complicated than this because we have
原子中有很多电子原子中不仅有单个电子
many electrons in an atom many an
electrons in atom not just a single
电子，这意味着我们必须跟踪整个角动量
electron and that means we have to keep
track of the entire angular momentum
大写L是轨道角的所有电子的总和
capital L that's the sum over all the
electrons of the orbital angular
每个电子的动量，然后是每个电子的总自旋角动量
momentum of each electron and then the
total spin angular momentum of each of
电子，当然总的角动量就是总的
the electrons and of course the total
angular momentum altogether is the total
轨道加上总旋转，您可能会从冒险中获悉
orbital plus the total spin and as you
probably learned from your adventures in
clebsch-gordon系数，您可以使用非常复杂的方法进行相加
clebsch-gordon coefficients that you can
have very complicated ways of adding
将角动量（例如两个自旋1/2扫描）相加在一起
together angular momenta for example to
two spin 1/2 scan add together to make a
单重态或三重态，然后事情会变得非常混乱，如果您有20
singlet or triplet and then things get
really messy and if you have 20
您原子中的电子可以加在一起，也可以通过两种疯狂的方式加在一起
electrons in your atom they can add
together and also two crazy ways and so
我们需要一些东西来指导我们弄清楚这些电子是怎么回事
we need something to guide us to figure
out how it is that these electron
角矩将要加起来，我们必须指导我们的第一件事是
angular momenta are going to add up
first thing that we have to guide us is
原子的壳结构，所以让我们回想起
the shell structure of the atom so let's
remember back to the beginning of the
术语壳结构，我们有两个定律帮助我们解决了第一个问题：
term shell structure we had two laws
that helped us out the first was the
Aufbau原理，基本上是弓形，我相信在德国意味着建筑
Aufbau principle which basically a bow
which in german i believe means building
或构造它意味着您一次填充一次炮弹，然后第二次填充
up or construction it means you fill up
shells one at a time and the second
我们所遵循的原则是玛德隆的玛德隆规则，该规则告诉我们
principle we had was madelung's
madelung's rule which told us in which
我们应该开始填充填充壳，这样可以帮助我们
order we should start filling filling
shells so that's going to help us out a
很多，对我们有很大帮助的原因是，
lot and the reason that's going to help
us out a lot is because there's an
填充壳的重要原理
important principle that a filled shell
l等于s等于j等于零填充时完全没有角动量
has l equals s equals j equals zero no
angular momentum at all in a filled
壳为什么这么好，我们使每个轨道都充满了自旋和每个轨道
shell why is that well we filled every
orbital with a spin up and every orbital
向下旋转，则总旋转为零，向上旋转的次数等于
with spin down so the total spin is zero
the number of ups is equal to the number
关于ELL的表现如何，我们进行了自旋
of down
how about ELLs well we spin we've filled
所有lz +状态，我们将所有lz-状态均等地填充到填充的外壳中
all the lz+ states and we equally filled
all the lz- states in in a filled shell
所以L Z彼此抵消，Lu最终退出的总数为零
so the L Z's all cancel each other and
the total Lu end up getting out is zero
所以填充的壳根本没有角动量，这意味着我们仅
so a filled shell is has no angular
momentum at all and that means we only
只看填充壳的部分好看填充壳的部分
only look at part filled shells look at
part filled shells okay so that's going
对我们有很大帮助，但您仍然可以将一部分装满三个
to help us out a lot but still you can
have a part filled shell with three four
里面有五个六七个电子和一个部分充满的劳特壳（如果是）
five six seven electrons in it and a
partially filled laut shell if it's a
大壳，您可以知道部分填充的壳中有13 14个电子，因此
big shell you can have you know 13 14
electrons in a partially filled shell so
幸运的是，这仍然可能非常复杂。
this could still be pretty complicated
fortunately we have a set of rules that
帮助我们弄清楚这些有角度的Mendte是如何相加的，这些是已知的
helps us figure out how these angular
Mendte add together and these are known
匈奴继弗雷德里克·洪德之后匈奴的统治
as huns rules
Hun's rules after frederique hund and he
早在1925年的第一年就将它们写下来了
wrote them down actually first 1925 a
very long time ago back in the early
量子力学的日子，人们正在学习
days of quantum mechanics just when
people were learning about shells of
现在我可能不知道Zots上的原子在德语中是什么意思
atoms now I may not know what on Zots
means in German I may not know what
alpha在德语中是指，但我知道引擎盖在德语中是指狗，所以无论如何
alpha means in German but I know that a
hood means dog in German so whatever
这是值得的，这是狗的规则，但嗯，所以规则1规则1电子自旋
that's worth these are the dogs rules
but um so rule 1 rule 1 electron spins
如果可以的话，将一条直线旋转一条直线，换句话说，您可以最大化所有
spins a line a line if they can if they
can in other words you maximize s all
对，所以这实际上是一个非常好的规则，因为它有点像是
right so this is actually a very nice
rule because it's kind of like being a
铁磁体中的所有自旋线都可以使您最大化
ferromagnet in a ferromagnet you get all
your spins to a line and you maximize
总的自旋不是铁磁体，因为我们只是在说
the total spin it's not really a
ferromagnet because we're just talking
这里只有一个原子，所以它只是有限数量的电子，而不是整个
about a single atom here so it's just a
finite number of electrons not a whole
你知道整个固体电子很大，但至少具有相同的定性
物理学所以你能理解为什么电子自旋会想要
physics so can you understand why it is
that the electron spins would want to
好吧，好吧，为什么为什么要把规则1做好第一件事不是因为
align well ok so why why rule 1
well the first thing it is not because
波兰pol相互作用的偶极-偶极相互作用
of Dai Poland i pol interactions
dipole-dipole interactions between the
自旋为什么不可以呢自旋确实有偶极矩和偶极矩
spins why not yes the spins do have
dipole moment and the dipole moments
会相互作用，但如果您尝试计算偶极子相互作用
will interact but if you try to
calculate the dipole dipole interaction
两个偶极子之间的强度，其偶极矩为玻尔磁子
strength between two dipoles whose
dipole moment is a Bohr Magneton in a
单个原子太小了，它是如此之小，您可以完全将其扔掉
single atom it's insanely small it's so
small you can just completely throw it
完全无关紧要，因此保持它重要不是因为这个
out totally irrelevant so it's not
because of this that's important to keep
请记住，这是由于库仑相互作用所致。
in mind what it is due to is due to
Coulomb interaction due to Coulomb let's
看看我们是否能弄清楚为什么库仑相互作用会关心电子
see if we can figure out why Coulomb
interaction would care if the electron
自旋对齐或对齐不正确，因此如果打开大多数固态
spins were aligned or not aligned well
so if you open up most solid state
物理书籍或大多数形式的物理书籍，通常会告诉您一些
physics books or most physics books of
any sort they usually tell you some
关于为什么电子自旋想要对准以及为什么是这样的故事
story about why it is that electron
spins want to align and why it is that
在这方面服从人的角色，故事在质量上是对的
one's role is obeyed in this respect and
the story is sort of qualitatively right
但这有很多问题，所以这是一个警告，我想我给了
but it has a lot of things wrong with it
so this is a warning I think I gave a
本书中的行为有很多警告，因此您可以阅读我们将要详细介绍的内容。
lot of caveats in the act in the in the
book so you can read the details we'll
先讲讲这个故事我先讲童话
go through this a little bit tell the
story first I'll tell the fairy tale
首先，我将向您解释为什么童话故事不完全正确
first then I'll explain to you why the
fairy tale isn't exactly right to have a
更好地了解实际发生的事情，以便弄清楚为什么会这样
better idea of what actually is going on
so in order to figure out why it is that
库仑相互作用很重要，让我们回想一下您是否具有两个波函数
Coulomb interaction cares let's recall
if you have a wavefunction for two
波动函数的电子应分解成轨道部分
electrons that wave function should be
decomposed into the orbital part which
取决于两个原子的位置对不起两个电子和自旋部分
depends on the position of the two atoms
sorry two electrons and the spin part
现在取决于两个电子的自旋
which depends on the spins of the two
electrons now the overall wave function
必须是反对称的，因为电子是费米子，所以这告诉我们
must be anti symmetric because electrons
are fermions and so that tells us that
如果Chi自旋等于使两个自旋指向相同的方向（如向上）
if Chi spin equals having both spins
pointing in the same direction like up
如果自旋对齐，则上下或同时指向侧面，这是
up down down or both pointing sideways
if the spins are aligned then this is
这是对称的然后是轨道部分
this is then symmetric symmetric then
the orbital part
叹息球是反对称的，这意味着如果我们将叹息轨道写为a
sigh orb is anti-symmetric what that
means is if we write sigh orbital as a
R 1减去R 2的函数，我们取R 1至R 2，波动函数必须为0
function of R 1 minus R 2 we take R 1 to
R 2 the wave function has to go to 0
因为如果采用反对称函数，然后采用
because the if you take an
anti-symmetric function and you take its
函数的参数必须为0，反对称必须为0
argument to 0 the function must go to 0
anything anti-symmetric has to go
在0处通过0表示什么，这意味着电子不能
through 0 at 0 so what does that mean
what that means is that electrons cannot
彼此靠近不能靠近
get close to each other cannot get close
彼此靠近，您可能会认为库仑相互作用会在乎
close to each other and you might think
that the Coulomb interaction would care
关于这一点，的确是通常讲的故事，所以这个故事
about that and indeed that's the story
that's usually told so the story goes
如果自旋对齐，则有点像这样，因为
kind of like this if the spins are
aligned then because of the symmetry of
波函数使电子无法彼此靠近，这使得
the wave function the electrons can't
get close to each other and that makes
库仑互动很高兴，因为库仑互动不希望
the Coulomb interaction happy because
the Coulomb interaction doesn't want the
电子彼此靠近，因此能量自然降低
electrons to get close to each other
either so the energy is naturally lower
因为电子彼此之间保持更远的距离，所以
because the electrons are staying
farther apart from each other ok it's
几乎是正确的，但是它不是真的正确，并且它不是真的正确的原因是
almost right but it's not really right
and the reason it's not really right is
因为更重要更重要的是电子原子核
because really more important more
important is the electron nucleus
原子核原子核不是电子，而是一种非常
nucleus nucleus not the electron
electron and it's it's sort of a very
电子核与电子之间的细微差异是因为
subtle difference between electron
nucleus and electron electron because
到最后都是库仑的互动，但让我尝试解释一下
it's all Coulomb interaction at the end
of the day but let me try to explain
我的意思是，所以让我们想象一下，我们在这里有一个核，然后我们有两个
what I mean by this so let's imagine we
have a nucleus here and then we have two
自旋的自旋是反对齐的，所以因为自旋是反对齐的，所以它们
spins who spins are anti aligned so
because the spins are anti aligned they
可以彼此靠近，特别是一个电子可以进入
can get close to each other and in
particular one electron can get in
原子核中另一个电子之间的关系现在可以记得我们去的时候
between the other electron in the
nucleus ok now remember when we went
回来，我们谈到了电负性和电离能
back and we talked about
electronegativity and ionization energy
当一个电子可以进入
when one electron can get inside the
orbit of the
其他的它可以屏蔽核，可以屏蔽来自核的电子，
other it can screen the nucleus it can
screen the electron from the nucleus and
使有效核电荷看起来更小，结果是
make the effective nuclear charge look
smaller as a result the electron on the
外面的约束力弱，因为它看到的有效核电荷较小
outside is weakly bound because it sees
a smaller effective nuclear charge on
另一方面，如果对齐电子的自旋，则电子将无法
the other hand if you align the spins of
the electrons then the electrons can't
彼此靠近，尤其是这个电子不能
get close to each other and in
particular this electron cannot get
在这个电子轨道内部，它无法从原子核中屏蔽掉这个电子
inside this electrons orbit and it can't
screen this electron from the nucleus so
结果，电子被牢固地束缚，这是更多的原因
as a result the electrons are strongly
bound and this is a more of the reason
为什么将两个电子自旋对齐会降低能量
of why it is that the it's lower energy
to have the two electron spins aligned
因为然后两个电子牢固地结合到原子核上
because then the two electrons are
strongly bound to the nucleus and that
降低他们的精力，所以这是hons第一个统治的诚实原因
lowers their energy okay so that's more
of the honest reason why hons first rule
适用，所以我们甚至可以概括匈奴
applies okay
so let's we can even generalize huns
如果我们想要的话，可以从原子到分子滚动，假设我们有一个分子
roll-up from atoms to molecules if we
want so suppose we have a molecule
分子假设我们有一个带有两个正核的分子，说两个
molecules suppose we have a molecule
with two positive nuclei and say two
如果两个电子自旋对齐，则这里的电子完全相同。
electrons up here it's exactly the same
physics if the two electron spins align
那么电子必须彼此分开而不能屏蔽
then the electrons have to stay apart
from each other and they can't screen
互相从核中旋转，而自旋反对齐，则它们可以
each other from the nucleus whereas the
spins are anti aligned then they can get
彼此之间，他们可以筛选核，最后结合
inside of each other and they can screen
the nucleus and in the end the binding
较弱，因此洪德法则希望旋转是反对齐洪德法则仍然
is weaker so hund's rule wants the spins
to be anti align the hund rule still
想要旋转甚至在分子中对齐
wants spins to align even in a molecule
但这必须与其他事物竞争，而另一事物必须
but that has to compete with something
else and the other thing that has to
与之竞争的是共价键，债券希望事前对齐，事前对齐
compete with is a covalent bonding bond
wants ante aligned ante aligned what's
我们称我们在两个轨道上拥有共价键时学到的东西
we call what we learned about covalent
bonding when we had orbitals on two
原子都具有能量e而不是当原子彼此靠近时它们形成
atoms both with energy e not when the
atoms come close together they form
一个键合和反键合的轨道，我们想将两个电子都放入
a bonding and anti-bonding orbital and
we want to put both electrons in the
反结合轨道，我们必须反对准它们的自旋以形成单线态，
anti-bonding orbital we have to anti
align their spins to make a singlet and
使它们都处于较低的能量状态，因此Hunza和
put them both in a lower energy state so
there's a competition between Hunza and
分子是共价键物理与洪德规则之间的竞争
molecules is a competition between
covalent bonding physics and hunds rules
物理学中的一个想要旋转以对齐其中一个想要旋转以
physics one of them wants the spins to
align one of them wants to spins to
反对齐，所以要弄清楚一个分子要复杂得多
anti-align so it's a lot more
complicated in a molecule to figure out
如果旋转对齐，或者如果不对齐，那么您应该知道那两个
if spins align or if they don't so when
you should just be aware that those two
互相竞争好吧，这是一个人的第一法则
are competing with each other okay all
right so that's one's first rule it
告诉我们，如果有壳的话，自旋会尽量对齐
tells us as the spins will try to align
if they can so if you have a shell
小于1/2填充，您可以将所有电子指向相同
that's less than 1/2 filled you can put
all of the electrons pointing the same
方向当您充满时，您必须开始将电子放入
direction when you get to have filled
you have to start putting electrons in
向相反的方向，因为您已经用所有
in the opposite direction because you've
filled all the states with all the
电子方向相同，但在一定程度上可以
electrons in the same direction but to
the extent that they can the electrons
现在我们将始终尝试统一，说我们仍然必须弄清楚会发生什么
will always try to align now that said
we still have to figure out what happens
到轨道的自由度，所以规则2非常相似，基本上是L
to the orbital degree of freedom so rule
2 is very similar which is basically L
被最大化以服从规则1到规则1，这更重要，所以让我们
is maximized to subject to rule 1 to
rule 1 which is more important so let's
看看我们是否可以举一个例子，这可能是解释这个问题的最简单方法
see if we can do an example of this
probably the easiest way to explain this
是为了展示它是如何工作的，所以让我们考虑一个亚当的舞台
is to show how it works so let's
consider a proscenium Adam this is
原子数原子数是59邪恶的59，在56中等于填充
atomic number atomic number is 59
evil's 59 which in 56 equals filled
炮弹，我认为它充满了炮弹，持续了6秒
shells
I think it's filled shells up to 6 s
实际上，这意味着我们已经充满了炮弹加上3个电子，所以59等于
actually so that means we have filled
shells plus 3 electrons ok so 59 equals
充满的壳加上F中的3个电子壳中的4f中只有3个电子
filled shells plus 3 electrons in the F
shell 3 electrons in 4f in well just F
外壳F为l等于3记住s PDFG，所以f在0 1 2 3 F为l等于3
shell F is l equals 3 remember s P D F G
so f at 0 1 2 3 F is l equals 3
所以我们可以写出所有赢得FL座位等于3的轨道2
so we can write out all the orbitals won
the seat for F L equals 3 there's 2 L
从负3 LZ到正1的轨道等于负3到正3，所以我们写
plus 1 orbitals going from minus 3 LZ
equals minus 3 to plus 3 so let's write
他们全部出来，所以LZ等于我们有负3负2负1 0 1 2 3负3负
them all out so LZ equals we have minus
3 minus 2 minus 1 0 1 2 3 minus 3 minus
2减1为0 1 2 3，我们现在必须在这些轨道中放入3个电子
2 minus 1 is 0 1 2 3 and we have to put
3 electrons in those orbitals now the
第一法则hons第一法则说，我们放入的电子必须有它们的
first rule hons first rule says that the
electrons we put in have to have their
旋转对齐，所以我们知道我们必须对齐旋转，然后
spins aligned so that's so we know we
have to have aligned spins and then what
我们想要做的就是我们要最大化l在满足所有
we want to do is we want to maximize l
subject to the condition that all the
自旋是对齐的，所以我们可以考虑让我们尝试最大化LZ，我们会做
spins are aligned so we can think well
let's try to maximize LZ and we would do
通过将电子尽可能地移到最右边，我们将得到
that by putting the electrons as far to
the right as possible and we would get
LZ等于6 3加2加1现在我们也可以尝试将它们放到最左边
LZ equals 6 3 plus 2 plus 1 now we can
also try to put them as far to the left
尽可能得到LZ的最小值
as possible and we get the smallest
value of LZ possible which would be
减6减3减2减1好的，所以如果我们能得到的最大LZ是
minus 6 minus 3 minus 2 minus 1 okay so
this if the largest LZ we can get is
加6，我们可以得到的最小LZ为负6，这意味着我们有L
plus 6 and the smallest LZ we can get is
minus 6 it means that the L we have l
在这种情况下等于6好吧，现在我们也可以
equals 6
in this case ok good now we can also
立即写下s是三分之二3旋转所有对齐的s等于
write down s immediately is three-halves
3 spins all aligned is s equals
三半，这就是洪德定律和洪德定律的运作方式
three-halves so that's how hund's rule
works and hund's rule
第二条规则也是由库仑相互作用驱动的，但是没有
second rule here is also driven by
Coulomb interaction but there aren't
很好的卡通图片来解释为什么在HoN中L最大化
very good cartoon pictures to explain
why it is that L is maximized in HoN
第二个角色，所以我很抱歉，这只是一个观察结果
second role so I apologize about that
it's just a you know it's an observation
那个引擎盖造了，没有人真正提出许多非常简单的解释
that hood made and no one's really come
up with many very simple explanations
在这一点上，嗯，所以这告诉了我们几乎所有我们需要知道的内容，但是
for it at this point um ok so this tells
us almost everything we need to know but
我们仍然有一个问题，即L如何与s对齐或反对齐，所以我们有
we still have the question of how does L
align or anti align with s so we have
规则3第三个规则上的规则3，L平行于s或L减去
rule 3 rule 3 on this third rule which
is either L is parallel to s or L minus
L与s um和平行
L is parallel to s
um and the way it goes is that J
J的绝对值是绝对L加上或减去绝对s（如果选择）-如果
absolute value of J is absolute L plus
or minus absolute s where we choose - if
我们有少于一半的填充壳少于一半的填充壳，这意味着
we have if less than half filled shell
less than half filled meaning that the
以其角动量和轨道角反旋转
spins anti aligned with their angular
momentum and with their orbital angular
一半，一半以上就可以了，所以这是第三个规则
man half it's more than half filled okay
so that's one's third rule which tells
您如何了解轨道和旋转角度Mendte如何彼此对齐或
you how the orbital and spin angular
Mendte either aligned with each other or
现在彼此反对齐，所以在这种情况下，例如我们这里的主席团
anti aligned with each other now so for
example in this case here Presidium we
壳的填充少于一半，所以J等于6减去我们选择的三分之二
have less than a half filled shell so J
equals 6 minus three-halves we choose
负号，因为它小于填充的一半，这使我们的J等于9
the minus sign because it's less than
half filled and that gives us J equals 9
一半，所以我们知道关于主席团的所有信息，我们知道
halves okay so we know everything there
is to know about Presidium we know what
L是我们知道s在哪里，我们知道从狩猎卷中知道J是什么，所以为什么它是
it L is we know where s is we know what
J is from hunt rolls okay so why it's
狩猎第三条法则是正确的狩猎第三条法则实际上与
hunts third rule true well hunts third
rule is actually a little bit unlike the
另外两个是因为它不是由交互驱动的，而是由驱动的
other two because it's not driven by
interactions it's actually driven by
它是由规则三驱动的，它来自自旋轨道的规则三
something else it's driven by rule three
is from rule three from spin orbit
耦合自旋轨道实际上是相对论效应自旋轨道耦合
coupling spin orbit which is actually a
relativistic effect spin orbit coupling
实际上，基本上就是当我们写下哈密顿量时
and in fact it is just it's basically
that when we wrote down the Hamiltonian
我们省略了一个小术语，即自旋轨道项，它取下一个项，因此
we left out a small term the spin orbit
term which takes the following term so
我将其写为Delta EIJ，这是我们忽略的哈密顿量的一小部分，
I'll write it as Delta EIJ a small piece
of the Hamiltonian we left out which we
可以写成所有电子轨道角动量的α和
can write as alpha sum over all the
electrons orbital angular momentum of
电子点缀着电子的自旋角动量就可以了
the electron dotted with the spin
angular momentum of the electron okay
现在汉密尔顿方程中的alpha大于零，所以我的意思是
now in this Hamiltonian alpha is greater
than zero and so I mean you can sort of
看到这将使轨道角动量和自旋
see that this is going to make the
orbital angular momentum and the spin
角动量计数器对齐以使其尽可能负
angular momentum counter align to make
this as negative as possible you're
要旋转的是贝尔兰加精神
going to have to
the spin is up the or Berlanga mentum
想下来等等，但您可能会很好奇
wants to be down and so forth but you
might wonder well what about this
业务大约一半装满了贝壳，不到一半超过一半
business about half filled shells in
less than a half thousand more than half
充满贝壳，似乎有点奇怪，事实证明那一点
filled shells that seems a little bit
strange it turns out that that little
奇怪的清单实际上只是来自簿记，您只需要小心
strange list is actually just from
bookkeeping you just have to be careful
关于簿记，每个进入的电子总是跟随
about the bookkeeping every electron
that goes in is always following the
同样的规则遵循hunds规则1遵循hunds规则2，然后尝试使其
same rule follow hunds rule 1 follow
hunds rule 2 and then try to make this
尽可能小，如果您遵循该规则，您将始终得到
as small as possible and if you if you
follow that rule you will always get
洪德法则3让我们一秒钟看看它是如何工作的
hund's rule 3 let's see how that works
for a second let's consider a case where
我们不知道D外壳，所以在广告外壳中，我们的LZ等于-2减1，
we have I don't know a D shell so in a d
shell we have L Z equals -2 minus 1 and
1 2 3 LZ等于-2减去1 0 1 2这些就是可能性
1 2 3 L Z equals -2 minus 1 0 1 2 those
are the possibilities let's put one
如果你在里面放一个电子的话，它就很简单
electron in if you put one electron in
it while ok it's pretty simple it wants
最大化其自旋角动量，因此自旋井只有一种选择
to maximize its spin angular momentum so
the spin well it only has one choice you
旋转1/2，这样很容易，并且它想最大化其轨道角动量为
spin 1/2 so that's easy and it wants to
maximize its orbital angular momentum as
好，所以我们可以把它放在这里或现在的电子路径上
well so we can put this the the electron
way over here or way over here now if
如果要使旋转降低，则希望将ll点Sigma最小化
you want to minimize the ll dot Sigma if
we put it if we make the spin spin down
那么您将其放在此处，以使Sigma Sigma Z等于负1/2
then you would put it over here so that
Sigma Sigma Z equals minus 1/2
但LZ等于加1/2，所以Sigma点L的乘积为负，这就是我们
but LZ equals plus 1/2 so the product of
Sigma dot L is negative which is what we
希望我们希望使该术语尽可能地否定，然后确定
want we want to make that term as
negative as possible ok and then sure
这两个JZ的总和是LZ减去Sigma Z，对不起LZ加Sigma Z是
enough the sum of these two JZ is L Z
minus Sigma Z sorry LZ plus Sigma Z is
三分之二，并声称Weesa的壳不到一半，所以J
three-halves and as claimed
Weesa less than a half filled shell so J
是2和1/2的差额，所以基本上可以告诉你
is the difference of 2 and 1/2 okay so
that works basically just telling you
这样，当您添加时，可能有1/2小于一半的填充壳旋转
that when you add you might have 1/2
less than half filled shell the spin and
轨道指向相反的方向，所以自旋轨道是
the orbit went to be pointing the
opposite direction so spin orbit is
负面的，这很容易，现在当我们进入半填充的外壳时会发生什么
negative that's easy ok now what happens
when we get to a half-filled shell when
我们得到一个半满的壳LZ，我们等于负
we get to a half-filled shell LZ we have
equals minus
二减一零一二当我们半满时，我们现在拥有这五个状态
two minus one zero one two we have these
five states now once we're a half-filled
外壳，我们必须将所有五个旋转对齐，因为我们要对齐所有
shell we have to put in all five spins
aligned because we want to align all the
自旋，所以在这里，我们等于五个一半，五个自旋都指向
spins so here we have s equals five
halves five spins all pointed in the
方向相同，但L等于零，因为我们已经填补了所有负数
same direction but L here equals zero
because we've filled all the negative
状态和所有加号状态都还好，所以这没问题
states and all the plus states as well
okay so here it's no problem
我的意思是，匈奴人第三卷甚至都不适用，因为L为零，所以旋转
I mean Huns third roll doesn't even
apply because because L is zero so spin
就是你的绝对J，只是旋转角度，所以我们
is just your absolute J's it's just it's
just that it's just a spin angular so we
现在不必担心L，我们再添加一个电子，这样当您
don't have to worry about about L now
let's add one more electron so when you
再加上一个电子LZ等于5减1减2减1 0 1 2
add one more electron LZ equals go minus
1 out of 5 minus 2 minus 1 0 1 2 we put
所有这些家伙都旋转下来，我们再增加一个电子，那一个电子会去哪里
all these guys spin down we add one more
electron where does that one electron go
好吧，它仍然想要满足这个条件，它想要自己旋转
well ok it still wants to satisfy this
condition that it wants its own spin
角动量指向其轨道角动量的相反方向，因此它必须走
angular momentum to point opposite its
orbital angular momentum so it has to go
然后旋转起来，所以我们必须把它放在这里，所以我们放入的最后一个电子
and spin up so we have to put it over
here so this last electron we put in has
Sigma Z等于正负1/2，但LZ等于负2，这仍然让它高兴
Sigma Z equals plus 1/2 but LZ equals
minus 2 and that still makes it happy
因为Sigma Z指向LZ的对面，但现在注意这里发生了什么
because Sigma Z is pointing opposite LZ
but now notice what's going on here the
总SZ总SZ实际上仍然是负数实际上是负数
total SZ the total SZ is actually still
negative is actually negative what it's
负2对，所以我放入的最后一个电子指向总数
negative 2 right so the last electron
that I put in was pointing up the total
自旋实际上仍然指向下方，即使l LZ在这里
spin is actually still pointing down so
and even though the l LZ is here is
减去2，因为一半填充的半壳的LZ总数等于0
minus 2 the total because the half the
half filled shell had LZ total equals 0
我们添加了一个电子，该电子朝上，但总自旋角
we added one electron that electron is
pointing up but the total spin angular
动量仍然指向下方，因此总旋转角度
momentum is still pointing down
so here the the total spin angular
总轨道角动量中的动量现在指向相同
mentum in the total orbital angular
momentum are now pointing the same
方向，我们仍然遵循相同的规则
direction and we were still just
following the same rule that each
电子想要抵消其自旋和轨道角动量的对准
electron wants to counter align his spin
and his orbital angular momentum
彼此，换句话说，我们来的原因是我们来到簿记
each other so in other words the reason
we came we came to this bookkeeping
问题是因为当我们有一个半满的外壳时，我们有s，它不是
problem is because when we have a
half-filled shell we have s which is non
零，但是当我们再增加一个电子时，L就是零
zero but L is zero when we add one more
electron the net spin of the whole
系统指向那个旋转的相反方向
system is pointing in the opposite
direction of the spin of that one
我们添加的电子，所以这就是为什么第三个规则在
electron we added so that's why one's
third rule has this complication at
一半的外壳是透明的，希望可以，好吧，对不起，我的意思是我
half-filled shell is that clear yeah
hopefully okay all right sorry I mean I
知道这很令人困惑，但是生活有时就是这样，所以我们必须处理
know it's confusing but but that's the
way life is sometimes so we have to deal
这样就可以了，所以鉴于我们知道LS和J，我们可以写下我们的
with it okay so given that we know LS
and J we can then write down our
哈密​​顿量，我们能做的第一件事是我们可以做L加GS做同样的事情
Hamiltonian well first thing we can do
is we can take L plus GS do the same
λG因子技巧，并将其重写为一些G有效时间J，其中J为L
lambda G factor trick and rewrite that
as some G effective times J where J is L
再加上其他，然后我们可以针对这些角度写下有效的哈密顿量
Plus else and then we can write down our
effective Hamiltonian for these angular
Momenta是G有效的J mu B BJ，我们可以用
momenta which is G effective J mu B BJ
and we can do statistical mechanics with
这种汉密尔顿式的，所以提醒您这是如何工作的
this kind of Hamiltonian so to remind
you how this works this is something
您去年所做的，所以举一个非常简单的例子，让我们举J
that you did last year so example take a
really simple example let's take J
等于1/2且G因子为2，因此自旋可以指向整体
equals 1/2 and a G factor of 2 so a spin
can point up with this this overall
角质子能指向上或指向下，两种可能的能量是
angle mentum can point up or can point
down and the two possible energies are
然后加上和减去玻尔磁子乘以磁场，我们可以写出
then plus and minus Bohr Magneton times
magnetic field we can then write the
此系统的分区函数，是的两个状态的总和
partition function for this system which
is the sum over the two states of the of
角动量，即使是负beta u也等于B加e等于正beta mu D等于
the angular momentum even the minus beta
u be B plus e to the plus beta mu D be
从分区功能，我希望这一切看起来都很熟悉，我们可以编写免费的
from the partition function I hope this
all looks familiar we can write the free
能量KBT log Z我们可以写出磁矩磁矩是猜测
energy KBT log Z we can write the
magnetic moment magnetic moment is guess
带有减号的地方在这个地方加入这个减号，我得到一个减号
with the minus sign join this minus sign
here somewhere I get there's a minus
缺少能量的迹象，我们可以写磁
sign missing
energy we can then write the magnetic
现在的DF DB，我相信您去年就这样做了，如果没有，您会
moment DF DB which I believe you did
this last year and if you didn't you'll
今年再做一次beta UVB，它具有针对小B小B的转换
do it this year again beta UVB it has
this transform for small B small B this
变成βμB B平方乘以磁场，然后磁化
becomes just beta mu B squared times
magnetic field then the magnetization
大写m是每体积的力矩每体积的力矩是每次旋转的力矩
Capital m which is moment per volume
moment per volume is the moment per spin
M小M乘Rho自旋密度
M small M times Rho the density of spins
旋转的密度，然后我们可以得到磁化率Chi
density of spins and then we can get the
susceptibility Chi which is by
定义mu而不是DM D在B等于零时取，如果通过
definition mu not DM D be taken at B
equals zero and if you go through that
达到这个极限，您将得到Rho mu naught mu B平方超过KBT
take that limit you get Rho mu naught mu
B squared over KBT
希望从去年开始看起来很熟悉，这就是居里的
which hopefully maybe looks familiar
from last year this is known as Curie's
居里定律实际上，居里定律是任何时候
law Curie law in fact more generally
Curie's law is any time when the
磁化率在T上是一个常数，这确实很重要
susceptibility is some constant over T
which indeed this is so the important
关于居里定律的敏感性要注意的是
thing to notice about this Curie law
susceptibility is that it diverges at
低温，随着温度的升高，磁化率会发散
low temperature you have a divergent
susceptibility as temperature goes to
零，这实际上是正确的，也很有意义
zero and this is actually correct and
it's meaningful
磁化率在零温度下发散的原因是
the reason the susceptibility diverges
it to at zero temperature is because
温度为零，系统始终处于最低能量状态，因此如果
it's zero temperature the system is
always in the lowest energy State so if
你有一束自旋，无论磁场有多小，磁场都很小
you have a bunch of spins and you have a
tiny magnetic field no matter how tiny
磁场是一个最低能级
that magnetic field there's a lowest
energy state where the moment is aligned
磁场，所以即使磁场很小
with the magnetic field so even with an
arbitrarily small magnetic field the
时刻都对齐并指向该方向，这意味着您随后
moments all align and point that
direction which means you then have an
无限的磁化率，因为它只需要一个极小的磁场即可
infinite susceptibility because it takes
only an infinitesimal magnetic field to
将所有旋转方向定为相同方向，这样实际上
orient all the spins in the same
direction set clear so this is actually
当温度升高时，有意义的陈述开始旋转
a meaningful statement when you
the temperature then the spins start
整个地方都在波动，它们并没有全部指向
fluctuating all over the place and they
don't all point in the direction of the
磁场，我的意思是，它的方向可能有点模糊
magnetic field I mean it may be point
sort of vaguely in the back direction of
磁场，但并非完全沿磁场方向
magnetic field but not all exactly in
the direction of the magnetic field so
现在，随着温度的升高，磁化率下降
the susceptibility drops as you go to
higher temperature now more generally
比这个简单的旋转1/2计算首先暴饮四转
than this this simple spin 1/2
calculation for first binge a four spin
一般而言，J遵循相同的故事，只是我们从分区开始
J in general we follow the same same
story except we start with a partition
在JZ上求和的函数等于负J 2加J e至负beta
function which is sum over J Z equals
minus J 2 plus J e to the minus beta the
我认为状态J的自旋能量是J G，对J有效，然后是mu bb jz
energy of the spin in state J which is J
G effective for J then mu b b jz i think
我在这里暗示而没有指出b指向Z
i implied here without without stating
it that that b is pointing in the Z
应用于Z方向，否则我们将使用
direction that we apply to be in the Z
direction otherwise we would use a
不同的轴，如果我们将B放在X方向上，它将是J，
different axis and it would be J if we
put B in the X direction we would just
使用不同的基础，我们将JX减去J来计算-J对此感到抱歉
use a different basis where we count J X
from minus J - J sorry about that
好的，那么您要进行完全相同的操作，代数是一点
ok then you go through exactly the same
manipulations the algebra is a little
比起其他一些困难，您获得的功能比
bit more different difficult you get out
some more complicated functioning than
在ang上，这是一个称为Bruin函数的函数，我认为这有些混乱
at ang it's a function known as a Bruin
function it's some messy thing I think
您去年在统计机修课程中计算出它有一些双曲线正弦
you calculated last year in your stat
mech course it has some hyperbolic sines
和其中的双曲余弦比较混乱，但是出现了相同的故事
and hyperbolic cosines in it a little
more messy but the same story comes out
在一天结束时在一天结束时，您仍然会得到居里定律
at the end of the day at the end of the
day you still get a Curie law in the
出于相同的原因，它是一个常数除以T
sense that it's a constant divided by T
for exactly the same reason an
现在，无穷小场将所有矩定向在同一方向上
infinitesimal field will orient all the
moments in the same direction okay now
一路上实际上要注意的一件事是非常重要的一点
one thing actually to note along the way
which is quite important it's a little
顺便说一句是，该分区函数是B的函数
bit of an aside is to note that this
partition function is a function of B
仅在T上它不是b NT的功能可以
over T only it's not a function of b NT
separately ok
这实际上很重要，因为这意味着熵也将是
and that's actually important because it
means that the the entropy will also be
b相对于t的函数，并且它在我不知道的时候就被注意到了
a function of b over t only and that it
was noticed way back in I don't know
1900年代初期，我们的英雄之一是彼得·德拜（Peter Debye）
early 1900s by one of our hero is Peter
Debye
在这个课程中已经出现了几次，他注意到
has shown up several times already in
this course and he noticed that that
表示您可以使用系统进行以下实验
would mean that you could do the
following experiment you take a system
在给定温度下的磁场中，如果绝热地减少
in a magnetic field at a given
temperature if you adiabatically reduce
磁场绝热意味着熵必须保持固定
the magnetic field adiabatic means that
the entropy has to stay fixed the
绝热降低磁场温度必须成比例变化
adiabatically reduce the magnetic field
the temperature must change proportional
对磁场，这就是所谓的绝热退磁
to magnetic field this is what's known
as adiabatic demagnetization
去磁，这实际上是制作冰箱的好方法
demagnetization and it's actually a
really good way to make a refrigerator a
非常强大的冰箱，您需要在某些温度下使用系统
very powerful refrigerator you take a
system at some temperature in some
磁场，您可以减小磁场并保持熵
magnetic field you reduce the magnetic
field and in order to keep the entropy
固定绝热地改变事物，温度必须成比例地降低
fixed changing things adiabatically the
temperature must reduce proportionally
到磁场，这就是人们建立世界上一些最
to the magnetic field this is the way
people build some of the world's most
功能强大的冰箱可降到Millikelvin甚至Micro Kelvin
powerful refrigerators that get down to
millikelvin or even micro Kelvin
温度，因此了解和最终掌握技术是一件好事
temperature so it's a good thing to know
about and eventually the technique
当我们简单的近似于
breaks down and it basically breaks down
when our simple approximation of just
独立旋转，此分区功能最终会中断
independent spins and this partition
function being right eventually breaks
在非常低的温度下，我们将继续讨论下一个
down at very low temperatures we'll come
to that and next lecture the one after I
想一想，所以这基本上就是关于功率磁化的故事
think all right so this is basically the
story of power magnetism one atom at a
时间，但是当您一次开始将许多原子放在一起时，事情可能会发生
time but when you start putting together
many atoms at a time things can be
不同的是，这个词在浓缩物质界周围
different there's this phrase that goes
around the condensed matter community
每当您将很多东西放到一起时，更多的就是不同的
more is different whenever you put lots
of things together you can get different
物理学，所以我仍然会思考一次或一次旋转
physics so I'm still going to think what
in some sense one spin at a time or one
电子一次一次一个原子，但是当我们开始将其放入
electron at a time one atom at a time
but when we start putting it in the
一堆其他原子的环境事物可以开始改变，所以可以
environment of a bunch of other atoms
things can start changing so what can be
不同的地方出了什么问题，固体的不同之处
different what goes wrong and what is
different in the solid what different in
我们可以写下几件事
a solid different in a solid okay a
couple things we can write down
立即我们可以进行电子跳跃电子跳跃，如果
immediately one we can have electron
hopping electron hopping and if
电子从一个原子跳到另一个原子，我们期望得到
electrons hop from one atom to the next
we expect to get
带物理，我们希望获得电子带物理带，如果您有一个
band physics we expect to get electron
band physics bands and if you have a
部分填充的乐队，你有一个金属管和物理，你可以得到一个金属，
partially filled band you have a metal
tube and physics you can get a metal and
如果您在金属中，则期望具有多顺磁性，因此会产生包利
if you're in metal you expect to have
poly paramagnetism and therefore pauli
顺磁性，你会得到费米表面，部分顺磁性，如果你有
paramagnetism you get a Fermi surface
and partly paramagnetism and if you have
功率功率磁化率九倍能力减小了一倍。
power power magnetism the susceptibility
Sept ability is smaller by a factor of
大约超过EF的KBT，其原因是您仍然尝试翻转
roughly KBT over EF and the reason for
this is that you you still try to flip
施加磁场时会过度旋转，但必须服从宝力
over spins when you apply a magnetic
field but you have to obey the Pauli
排他性原则，这可以防止您将其中的大部分
exclusion principle and that prevents
you from flipping over a lot of them
只有一小部分会在磁场中翻转，所以
it's only a small number of them will
flip over in a magnetic field okay so
如果电子从一个跳到另一个，那可能是不同的一件事
that's one thing that can be different
if the electrons are hopping from one
原子到另一个原子，那么您可能会期望具有金属和pauli顺磁性
atom to another then you might expect to
have a metal and pauli paramagnetism
磁化率小得多，所以您可能会问我们什么时候不跳频
much smaller susceptibility so you might
ask well when when do we have no hopping
什么时候没有跳就没有跳，因为你知道为什么会
when is there no hopping is there no
hopping because you know why why would
他们从来没有跳过，为什么电子不会从一个原子跳到
they ever not hop why would the
electrons ever not hop from one atom to
下一口井基本上来自于当我们
the next well basically this comes from
interactions us when there's strong
互动，我们在谈论mod之前就已经讨论过了
interactions and we discussed this
before when we talked about mod
绝缘子我会提醒您，什么是Mod绝缘子？
insulators I'll remind you what a mod
insulators is Mott insulator is when you
每个位点只有一个电子，由于库仑相互作用，它可以防止
have one electron in each site and due
to the Coulomb interaction it prevents
您不会在该站点上拥有两个电子，那么您就有了
you from ever having two electrons on
the site and then you have this idea of
电子的交通阻塞，每个原子上有一个电子，没有人能
a traffic jam of electrons where there's
one electron on each atom and no one can
跳到他的邻居，因为他们都是因为已经有人
jump to his neighbors because they're
all because there's already someone
坐在那里，每个人都冻结了，但是只有一个电子在冻结
sitting there so everyone's frozen but
it's frozen with only one electron on
每个位点，因此您可以担心电子自旋或磁极以下
each site and so you can worry about
that electron spin or or below mag
角动量，可以重新定向，它非常好
angular momentum and that can be
reoriented and it makes a very nice
这样的功率磁铁，使这些绝缘子的高度至少在
power magnet that way so these menthe
insulators at height well at least at a
高温，我们将在下一个讲座中在低温下讨论它们
high temperature we'll talk about them
at low temperature in the next lecture
不久后，Magnus产生了相当不错的力量
long after make a fairly good power
Magnus
这就是第一点和第二点的不同点
so that's point one what can be
different in a solid point two of what
固然可以说环境可以事关环境可以
can be different as a solid is that the
environment can matter environment can
问题，并举例说明为什么可以假设您有
matter and to give you an example of why
that can be let's imagine that you have
长的四分之一晶胞中的一个原子，比它的宽高得多，并且
an atom in a long tetr-a g''l unit cell
which is much taller than it is wide and
您可能会想到，由于
you might imagine that in tetragonal
unit cell like this due to the
轨道角动量可能想要向上或指向的环境
environment the orbital angular momentum
might want to be pointing up or pointing
直接向下可能需要L指向上方或L指向下方而不是
down directly might want want L pointing
up or L pointing down and not in the
所以即使它是F电子，可能指向LZ也等于
middle so even if it was an F electron
which could point in LZ equals you know
从负3到正3一直是因为环境
all the way from minus 3 to plus 3 it's
still because of the environment it
可能更喜欢直接指向上方或下方，而不是指向
might prefer to point directly up or
directly down and not anywhere in the
中间，这可以改变整个故事，这就是所谓的
middle and that can change the story
quite a bit this is what's known as
晶体场分裂场分裂
crystal field splitting field splitting
原子环境倾向于确定允许的角矩的位置
where the environment of an atom tends
to fix which angular momenta are allowed
哪些不被允许，以及在这种情况下发生的一件事
and which ones are not allowed ok and
one thing that happens in this case
尤其重要的是有时候您会遇到这样的情况
which is particularly important is
sometimes you can get a situation where
晶体场实际上是相当普遍的力L基本上为0
a crystal field it's actually quite
common forces L to basically be 0 make
L的某种叠加，迫使它们为0，在这种情况下，
some sort of superposition of L's that
force them to be 0 in which case which
意味着总的J就是自旋s，而L没有贡献，所以
implies that the total J is just then
the spin s and L doesn't contribute so
即使您有F电子或部分填充的F壳，其中有很多
even if you had F electrons or partially
filled F shell where there's lots of
电子，您可能会想像它会因休斯角色而具有非零的L
electrons and you might imagine that it
would have a nonzero L by huns role
由于原子L的环境，可以强迫其为零，然后您
because of the environment of the atom L
can be forced to be zero and then you
只会获得自旋角动量，而不会获得轨道角动量
would only get the spin angular momentum
and not the orbital angular momentum
这是典型的过渡金属，她告诉您所谓的过渡
this is typical of transition metals
she tell you what's called of transition
金属，例如铬um，这就是众所周知的名字
metals things like chromium um this is
known as give it a name it's known as
当L基本上由于环境而从问题中除去时淬灭ml
quenching ml when L is basically removed
from the problem due to the environment
原子，这是过渡金属的典型特征，但不会发生不会发生
of the atom it's typical of transition
metals but does not occur does not occur
稀土元素会发生稀土元素或镧系元素和act系元素
occur for rare earths for rare earth
rare earth or lanthanides and actinides
地球原子，其原因有些微妙，但实际上并非如此
earth atoms and the reason for this is a
little subtle but actually not not that
复杂的原因是，在过渡金属中，部分
complicated the reason for this is that
in a transition metal the partially
填充的外壳是3D外壳，所以在这里我们有一个原子，可能是
filled shell is say the 3d shell so here
we have an atom and it's maybe the
填充最远的外壳是4s，部分填充的外壳是3d外壳
farthest out shell that's filled is 4s
the partially filled shell is a 3d shell
像这样的3d外壳，而3d外壳非常靠近
like this 3d shell like this and the 3d
shell is very close to the outer edge of
过渡金属中的原子是过渡金属，因此部分
the atom in the transition metal this is
transition metal and so the partially
填充的外壳强烈看到原子的环境，因为
filled shell sees the environment of the
atom quite strongly because the
电子非常靠近原子的边界，而在稀土中
electrons are very close to the boundary
of the atom whereas in the rare earths
地球在哪里，你可以拥有最外壳的东西
where our Earth's you can have something
where the outermost shell is something
像是6s，部分填充的外壳是4f，因此非常容易受到保护
like 6s and the partially filled shell
is 4f and so it's very protected from
环境，因为部分填充的壳半径要小得多
the environment because the partially
filled shell it's a much smaller radius
而不是整个原子，所以基本上对于部分填充的壳
than the atom as a whole so basically
the for the partially filled shell
甚至看不到环境，因为它与环境隔离开来
doesn't even see the environment because
it's so shielded from the environment by
原子中较大的轨道，所以或多或少地解释了为什么它是
the larger orbitals in the atom so it's
more or less explains why it is that the
稀土没有角质素的淬灭，而过渡
rare earths don't have quenching of
angular mentum whereas the transition
金属做的很好，这就是我们或多或少要说的一切
metals do all right so this is
everything we have to say more or less
关于力量'而不是ISM回到第一个方程式
about power
'not ISM back up to the first equation
我们今天在此处写在板上，并担心反磁性
we wrote on the board here today and
worried a little bit about diamagnetism
所以什么时候可以得到抗磁性，哪里有抗磁性
so when can we get diamagnetism when is
there diamagnetism well there a couple
您如何获得反磁性的第一种经典案例
ways that you can get diamagnetism the
first sort of classic case of when you
当您恰好有一个
get diamagnetism is when j equals zero
when you just so happen to have a
没有角动量来重新定向的情况
situation where there's no angular
momentum to reorient there's no
顺磁性，因为没有J，例如，如果您有一个
paramagnetism because there's no no J
and for example example if you have a
填充的壳，像稀有气体，L等于s等于J等于零，
filled shell like a noble gas that would
have L equals s equals J equals zero and
您无法重新定向任何磁矩，因为没有磁矩
you can't reorient any magnetic moment
because there is no magnetic moment to
重新定向，这样，在这种情况下，您基本上可以在
reorient so in that case you can
basically just throw out this term in
哈密​​顿量剩下的唯一东西就是哈密顿量的反磁项
the Hamiltonian the only thing left is
the diamagnetic term of the hamiltonian
还有可能导致反磁性的情况，我还应该提到
another case where you can get
diamagnetism I should also mention that
不仅可以填充壳，还可以填充分子轨道
not only you can have filled shell you
can also have filled molecular orbitals
您知道类似的分子轨道，就像我在我们
molecular orbitals which you know
similar like I mentioned this when we
谈到范德华键时，您有一个惰性原子如氮-
talked about van der Waals bonding you
have an inert atom like a nitrogen -
对不起像氮气这样的惰性分子-您可以将其视为
sorry an inert molecule like a nitrogen
- molecule which you can think of as
只是一堆填充的分子轨道，所以它的净J等于0
being just a bunch of a filled molecular
orbitals so it has a net J equals 0 at
分子水平，因此在这种情况下，实际上没有任何方向可以调整
the molecular level and so there's
really nothing to reorient in the case
氮转化为分子，因为所有分子轨道都被填充
of a nitrogen to molecule because all
the molecular orbitals are filled sort
类似于具有一个轨道壳的较大原子，
of analogous to to a larger atom with
orbitals that are orbital shells that
充满了另一种情况，你可以得到反磁性
are filled there's another situation
where you can get diamagnetism which is
当您患有肺泡炎时，您的顺磁性一直很弱
when you have when when you have pauli
paramagnetism is weak it's always weak
因为它的Chi较小，是KBT在EF上面写下的，
because it's Chi is smaller by wrote
this down above by KBT over EF which is
这是一个很大的因素，因此，如果您有铜之类的金属
a pretty big factor so if you have a
metal like copper or something like that
您会期望它是一个顺磁体，因为它具有旋转的方向，但是
you would expect it to be a paramagnet
because it has spins to reorient but
由于多排除原则，它们的方向不太理想，您
because of the poly exclusion principle
they don't reorient very well and you
在这种情况下，反磁性项具有
only get a very small susceptibility in
which case the diamagnetic term has a
有机会与顺磁性术语竞争，所以这是一个挑战
chance to compete with the paramagnetic
term and so here's a challenge you
应该问你的导师是铜的反磁铁还是顺磁性，除非
should ask your tutors is copper a
diamagnet or a para magnet and unless
他们去年我们在辅导这门课，在这种情况下，学生问他们
they we're tutoring this course last
year in which case students asked them
去年是同样的问题，所以四个新导师大多数都会把它弄错
the same question last year so four new
tutors most of them will get it wrong
大多数人会说它是金属，所以它是多对位磁铁，
most people will say that well it's a
metal so it's a poly para magnet and
的确具有泡利顺磁性物理学，但是它是如此的弱以至于
indeed it has the pauli paramagnetism
physics but that's so weak that the
反磁术语实际上有机会与之竞争，实际上
diamagnetic term here actually has a
chance to compete with it and in fact
对于铜，反磁性反而足够令人惊讶，所以您
for copper it turns out to be
diamagnetic surprisingly enough so you
当仅具有功率磁性的金属可以得到时
can with when metals which have only
power power magnetism you can get
反磁性赢得了挑战，也挑战了您的导师，看看有多少人
diamagnetism winning over also challenge
your tutors with that see how many get
很好，很快，我想我们可以在五分钟内完成
it right all right so very quickly I
think we can do this in five minutes we
可以计算出该反磁性项的影响，因此
can calculate the effect of this
diamagnetic term so the part of the
我们感兴趣的哈密顿量是e平方超过2m的平方，我们将
Hamiltonian we're interested in is e
squared over 2m a squared and we'll put
V在Z方向上，所以B等于BZ hat，所以我们可以写一个矢量势
V in the Z direction so B equals B Z hat
and so we can write a vector potential
一半的V越过R，这样del越过a等于B，则B越过2
one-half V cross R so that del cross a
equals B and that will then be B over 2
我想我们会写Y帽子X减去X帽子Y
I guess we'll write Y hat X minus X hat
Y you need enough so this term in the
然后，我们感兴趣的哈密顿量在8 m B上平方e×B平方x平方
Hamiltonian we're interested in is then
e squared over 8 m B squared x squared
加y平方，则该项在哈密顿量中的期望能量
plus y squared then the expectation
energy of this term in the Hamiltonian
我们在零温度下这样做很方便
which we're doing this at zero
temperature which is convenient to do
那就是能量的变化与自由能的变化相同
that's the change in the energy is the
same as the change in the free energy a
平方超过8 MB平方期望x平方加上y平方
squared over 8 M B squared
expectation of x squared plus y squared
因此磁矩为D减去预期能量DV
and so the magnetic moment is then minus
D expectation of energy DV
然后-B e在x平方加y平方的4m上平方
which is then - B e squared over 4m
expectation of x squared plus y squared
现在记得在上次演讲中我提到的那个
now remember in the last lecture I
mentioned to you that
反磁性有点像镜片定律，就像一圈电线，如果你
diamagnetism is a little bit like lenses
law it's like a loop of wire and if you
只有一圈电线，你从电流中得到的磁矩量
only have a loop of wire the amount of
magnetic moment you get from a current
绕过那圈电线与它的面积成正比，实际上
going around that loop of wire is
proportional to its area and indeed this
x平方加y平方的期望值是
expectation of x squared plus y squared
is the area enclosed by the orbital of
电子，因此非常类似于镜头定律，它实际上是在测量
the electron so it's quite analogous to
lenses law it's really measuring the
电流以与绕射定律给您的方式相同的方式绕过原子
currents going around the the atom in
the same way that lenses law gives you a
与绕线环流动的电流相关的磁铁
magnet associated with the current
running around the loop of wire
在球形原子中，计算x平方加y平方并不难
calculating x squared plus y squared
isn't so difficult in a spherical atom
因此，如果我们有一个球形原子，那么这些天大多数原子都是球形的，我们
so if we have a spherical atom most
atoms are spherical these days atom we
可以这样写：x平方加y平方的期望的三分之二
can write that as then two-thirds of
expectation of x squared plus y squared
再加上Z平方或R平方期望值的三分之二，因此我们可以
plus Z squared or two-thirds of
expectation of R squared and so we can
然后重写每个原子的磁矩，这里减去-6 m的平方
then rewrite the magnetic moment per
atom here is minus b e squared over 6 m
那6是因为将三分之二与1/4的时间相加
that 6 comes from putting together the
two-thirds with the 1/4 their times
R的平方期望，然后磁化强度是Rho的M倍，其中Rho
expectation of R squared and then the
magnetization is M times Rho where Rho
是整个系统中电子的电子密度，
is the density of electrons of electrons
in in the entire system and that gives
我们很好，就磁场而言，
us well we differentiate that with that
with respect to the magnetic field
我们将在此处获得等于M的零，然后减去M的零。
we'll get here chi equals nu nought the
M DB which is then minus mu naught e
R平方的原子期望值的Rho平方除以质量的6倍
squared Rho size of the atom expectation
of R squared divided by 6 times the mass
电子，这就是所谓的拉莫尔结果拉莫尔结果拉莫尔或
of the electron and this is known as the
larmor result larmor result larmor or
有时拉莫尔较大的面包车长沙板
sometimes larmor larger van long Shaban
反磁性的对不起，这是拉莫尔或朗伊人
diamagnetic
sorry this is larmor or Longy man
反磁性，剩下的两分钟就是现在的期望
diamagnetism and that's the expectation
of this now in the remaining two minutes
我要告诉你一些不可考量的东西，这个计算是
I'm going to tell you something that's
not examinable this this calculation is
考试的非常标准的方法是计算原子或某些系统的反磁性
very standard for exams calculate the
diamagnetism of an atom or some system
原子有不可检验的东西，那就是我们是
of atoms there's something that's non
examinable which is that we were a
抛弃顺磁性这个词有点太快了
little bit too fast in throwing away the
paramagnetic term the reason we were too
很快，我们就知道了，我们最初说的很清楚，功率磁项是
fast you know we were we we initially
said well the power magnetic term is
in的线性是B的二次方，因此我们将处理该项
linear in in be the diamagnet term is
quadratic in B so we'll treat this term
首先，然后仅当此术语碰巧很小但要处理此问题时
first and then only treat this one if
this term happens to be small but
实际上，我们应该多加注意，不要担心
actually we should be a little more
careful that we shouldn't worry about
这个词也是二阶的，如果我们对它仔细的话
this term at second order as well that
if we were careful about it we would
还必须写一些看起来像二阶扰动的术语
have to also write some term that looked
like this second order perturbation
结果且不等于n亩BB点L的0加GS 0的平方，这也是
result and not equal to 0 of n mu B B
dot L plus GS 0 squared this is also
磁场E的二次方-这个术语显然是负的
quadratic in magnetic field E - e n this
term is manifestly negative the sign of
二阶摄动理论显然是负的，所以它将
the second order perturbation theory is
manifestly negative and so it would
实际上给了我们顺磁性的贡献
actually give us a paramagnetic
contribution power mag contribution
在诺贝尔奖获得者之后，被称为范·弗莱克（Van Vleck）的强磁力范·弗莱克（Van Vleck）
known as Van Vleck power magnetism
Van Vleck after Nobel laureate who
发现它往往很小，但尤其是在以下情况下会发生
discovered it it tends to be small but
it can occur in particular in cases when
J等于零，但l和s不等于零，所以我们有J或L等于s但J
J equals zero but l and s are not equal
to zero so we have J or L equals s but J
等于L减去s等于零，它可能发生的原因是，如果您
equals L minus s equals zero and the
reason it can occur is because if you
记得当我们回到这里时，我们说过我们可以在
remember when we went back here and we
said that we could replace this term in
哈密​​顿量与J这两个项之和实际上是我们预先设定的
the Hamiltonian with J the sum of these
two terms we were actually presupposing
L的大小，s的大小和J的大小是固定的，但是
that the magnitude of L the magnitude of
s and the magnitude of J were fixed but
实际上，虽然旋转L＆S的位置不固定，但您可以在x'处获得激励x'
in fact you can have excitation x' where
you unfix though is where you rotate L&S
彼此远离并改变激发态下j的值
away from each other and change the
value of j in the excited states and you
可以得到这个的非零贡献，这样就不会发生
can get a nonzero contribution of this
then so this it doesn't tend to happen
对于稀有气体，因为稀有气体的L和s均为0，但存在
for noble gases because noble gases you
have L and s both being 0 but there are
元素周期表中的一些元素，我认为它少于1/2
some elements on the periodic table
which are I think it's one less than 1/2
根据洪德定律，在组合中L恰好等于s的填充壳为
a filled shell where L happens to equal
s in the combination by hund's rule is
零，这个项实际上可以出来，给你一个顺磁性的贡献
zero and this term can actually come out
and give you a paramagnetic contribution
也是不可考的，不用担心，这只适合您
as well that's not examinable don't
worry about it it's just for your
一般的教育，我们明天再谈磁性
general edification we'll talk more
about magnetism tomorrow see you then
您
you